<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>arch on ledoged.</title><link>https://ledoged.github.io/tags/arch/</link><description>Recent content in arch on ledoged.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 16:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ledoged.github.io/tags/arch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Arch Linux sleep causes freeze after wake up.</title><link>https://ledoged.github.io/posts/arch-linux-sleep-causes-freeze-after-wake-up/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ledoged.github.io/posts/arch-linux-sleep-causes-freeze-after-wake-up/</guid><description>Arch Linux freezing after sleep. The problem Whenever I do systemctl suspend, system sleeps normally. But after pressing the power button and power back on, PC totally freezes. No mouse movement, can&amp;rsquo;t change tty. Doing this without startx will result in same thing but tty can change except no response from keyboard at all.
Tried solutions There are multiple posts in the forum discussing this problem with non leading to a actual solution.</description></item><item><title>Get sound in Arch Linux</title><link>https://ledoged.github.io/posts/get-sound-in-arch-linux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ledoged.github.io/posts/get-sound-in-arch-linux/</guid><description>As a novice/beginner in using Linux, heck even a DIY distribution like https://archlinux.org/. I think it&amp;rsquo;s a very painful experience to even get sound in Arch. I figure if I write this down in a blog post so that others and myself can follow along make their own sound work.
Firstly make sure to upgrade Arch and packages.
sudo pacman -Syu Alright, now install pulseaudio which is like a software front-end which sits on top of alsa which is your kernel level sound mixer that directly talks to sound card.</description></item></channel></rss>