<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on ledoged.</title><link>https://ledoged.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on ledoged.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 16:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ledoged.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Arch Linux sleep causes freeze after wake up.</title><link>https://ledoged.github.io/posts/arch-linux-sleep-causes-freeze-after-wake-up/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ledoged.github.io/posts/arch-linux-sleep-causes-freeze-after-wake-up/</guid><description>Arch Linux freezing after sleep. The problem Whenever I do systemctl suspend, system sleeps normally. But after pressing the power button and power back on, PC totally freezes. No mouse movement, can&amp;rsquo;t change tty. Doing this without startx will result in same thing but tty can change except no response from keyboard at all.
Tried solutions There are multiple posts in the forum discussing this problem with non leading to a actual solution.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="arch-linux-freezing-after-sleep">Arch Linux freezing after sleep.</h1>
<h2 id="the-problem">The problem</h2>
<p>Whenever I do <code>systemctl suspend</code>, system sleeps normally. But after pressing the power button and power back on, PC totally freezes. No mouse movement, can&rsquo;t change tty. Doing this without <code>startx</code> will result in same thing but tty can change except no response from keyboard at all.</p>
<h2 id="tried-solutions">Tried solutions</h2>
<p>There are multiple posts in the forum discussing this problem with non leading to a actual solution. I used <code>journalctl</code> to figure out what errors could have resulted from previous boot. But there was non that was significant. The forum posts mentioned nouveau graphic drivers suck at power management, and I should install Nvidia proprietary drivers instead. But Nvidia drivers for my PC is so ancient its not updated in probably 10 years. Another mentioned how the WIFI driver would also affect the sleep process due to not powering off properly.</p>
<h2 id="conclusions">Conclusions</h2>
<p>I am stuck for now. This is extremely annoying as I use sleep almost daily on my Windows installation. This also confirms my that Linux is not that great for older hardware probably due to problems like this that don&rsquo;t exist on Windows.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>2023 is here.</title><link>https://ledoged.github.io/posts/redshift-setup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ledoged.github.io/posts/redshift-setup/</guid><description>New year. New setup.
🎉🎉🎉</description><content type="html">&lt;p>New year. New setup.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>🎉🎉🎉&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Get sound in Arch Linux</title><link>https://ledoged.github.io/posts/get-sound-in-arch-linux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ledoged.github.io/posts/get-sound-in-arch-linux/</guid><description>As a novice/beginner in using Linux, heck even a DIY distribution like https://archlinux.org/. I think it&amp;rsquo;s a very painful experience to even get sound in Arch. I figure if I write this down in a blog post so that others and myself can follow along make their own sound work.
Firstly make sure to upgrade Arch and packages.
sudo pacman -Syu Alright, now install pulseaudio which is like a software front-end which sits on top of alsa which is your kernel level sound mixer that directly talks to sound card.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a novice/beginner in using Linux, heck even a DIY distribution like <a href="https://archlinux.org/" title="Arch">https://archlinux.org/</a>. I think it&rsquo;s a very painful experience to even get sound in Arch. I figure if I write this down in a blog post so that others and myself can follow along make their own sound work.</p>
<p>Firstly make sure to upgrade Arch and packages.</p>
<pre><code>sudo pacman -Syu
</code></pre>
<p>Alright, now install <code>pulseaudio</code> which is like a software front-end which sits on top of <code>alsa</code> which is your kernel level sound mixer that directly talks to sound card.</p>
<p>At the same time install <code>alsa-utils</code> for some useful tools.</p>
<pre><code>pacman -S pulseaudio alsa-utils
</code></pre>
<p><code>alsa-utils</code> contain <code>alsa-mixer</code> which is good enough if you are a CLI freak. <code>alsa-mixer</code> is like a CLI volume control/mixer to control the volume coming out of your sound devices. Or if you don&rsquo;t like that, try to use <code>pavucontrol</code>.</p>
<pre><code>pacman -S alsamixer pavucontrol
</code></pre>
<p>If you are lucky you should have a literal deafening sound when you try to play any application with sound. Try to go on Youtube and play  video and see if you are deaf or not 💀.</p>
<p>Or if you are unlucky like me.. I got no sound because I plugged my earphone into an earphone jack that is in my monitor which is connected through HDMI. If you are using <code>alsa-mixer</code> press the hotkey to switch your sound cards to HDMI and see if the volume there is muted or not, in my case it was.</p>
<p>I am still experimenting with window managers (AwesomeWM) and trying to hotkey volume and get a widget that controls it. Once that&rsquo;s done I&rsquo;ll make another blog post on how to do it.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>New theme 😎</title><link>https://ledoged.github.io/posts/new-theme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ledoged.github.io/posts/new-theme/</guid><description>After tinkering and messing up inside Hugo, I changed some things up in this theme!
Next up is to implement some widgets to make my life easier..</description><content type="html">&lt;p>After tinkering and messing up inside Hugo, I changed some things up in this theme!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next up is to implement some widgets to make my life easier..&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Customizing</title><link>https://ledoged.github.io/posts/customizing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 16:20:38 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ledoged.github.io/posts/customizing/</guid><description>Customizing this site is kinda hard.
The original theme is kind of minimalist which is good if I want to add features but at the same time I want other features from other themes too. I&amp;rsquo;ve been referencing other themes to modify this theme.
Hugo is a pain in the butt. I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to learn Go but it&amp;rsquo;s going to be taking a while&amp;hellip;
In the mean time to test image uploading, here&amp;rsquo;s a cat.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Customizing this site is kinda hard.</p>
<p>The original theme is kind of minimalist which is good if I want to add features but at the same time I want other features from other themes too. I&rsquo;ve been referencing other themes to modify this theme.</p>
<p>Hugo is a pain in the butt. I&rsquo;ve been trying to learn Go but it&rsquo;s going to be taking a while&hellip;</p>
<p>In the mean time to test image uploading, here&rsquo;s a cat.</p>
<p><img src="/uploads/cute.jpg" alt=""></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Blog template test</title><link>https://ledoged.github.io/posts/blog-template-test/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ledoged.github.io/posts/blog-template-test/</guid><description>Testing</description><content type="html">&lt;h1 id="testing">Testing&lt;/h1></content></item><item><title>First Post</title><link>https://ledoged.github.io/posts/first-post/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 11:17:07 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ledoged.github.io/posts/first-post/</guid><description>A Test print(&amp;#34;Welcome to ledoged&amp;#34;)</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="a-test">A Test</h1>
<div class="highlight"><pre class="chroma"><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span class="k">print</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s2">&#34;Welcome to ledoged&#34;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</code></pre></div>]]></content></item></channel></rss>